Simply explained, open access means that it should be possible for anybody-
-To free of charge take part in research results-
-For example, scientific publications, by searching the internet.
This might not sound so remarkable-
-But the fact is that the open asset means a major change-
-For both the research world and the libraries that make the research available.
Open access is part of another current concept, open science.
In an open science system-
-In open access to scientific publications and research data
-But also such as open learning resources and citizen participation in research.
The government has decided that scientific publications and research data